



# Ryan, Paul McKenna

**Date of birth:** 08/12/1994 | **Nationality:** Irish, British | **Gender:** Male

Phone number: (+44) 7462881123 (Mobile) | Email address:

ryan.mckenna002@gmail.com | Website:

https://www.mckenna-technologies.com/ | Website:

https://github.com/RyanPaulMcKenna | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-mckenna-870847165/

Address: 2 Ambrose Street, YO104ED, York, United Kingdom (Home)

## **ABOUT ME**

I have worked in Scientific Computing, Machine Learning, Embedded Software Engineering and Robotics. Currently I am pursuing my PhD in Computer Science at The University of York, my research is focused on the intersection between Soft-Robotics and Robotic Deformable Object Manipulation. I want to help make robots safer, cheaper and better for working around people.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

17/02/2022 - 09/05/2023 Bristol, United Kingdom

#### EMBEDDED SYSTEMS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER MBDA

- Embedded development in C & C++ on Linux.
- Working with various micro controllers and communication protocols such as CAN, UART, I2C and SPI. Knowledge of DC motors and other components.
- Leveraging electrical engineering knowledge, schematic & PCB design.
- Experience working on unmanned or robotic systems.
- Control systems, control theory, robotics for machine learning

Address 3 Golf Course Ln, Bristol , BS34 7QS, Bristol, United Kingdom

25/04/2021 - 10/02/2022 Barcelona, Spain

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER MCKENNA TECHNOLOGIES**

- Operating as an independent Developer focused on Computer Vision and Machine learning. Using libraries such as OpenCV, Pytorch, Numpy, Pandas.
- Working on Linux systems in Python and C++. Working with SQL databases. Performing statistical analysis to fine tune model results.
- Provided expert hands-on technical advice, guidance, and consultancy to B2B clients, aligning relevant, viable technological solutions to ever-changing business needs

11/05/2018 - 15/04/2021 Manchester, United Kingdom

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER FLIXIR SOFTWARE**

- Worked through the full lifecycle of multiple projects, from concept design, through development, to testing and release for ITRAX (Productivity system for chemists).
- Integrating graphical libraries for computational chemistry into the management software, giving scientists the power to interactively develop and document the process of drug discovery using the well known python library CHEMDRAW.
- Created easy to understand, clean, reusable code for future use, developed according to design patterns and refactored as necessary.

- Working with big data, requiring data cleansing, augmentation, visualization and analysis. Integration of Machine learning models for business insights.
- Perform tasks such as Principal Component Analysis, Dimensionality Reduction, Normalization, feature extraction, de-noise, de-noising, sampling on customer data to inform future business and development goals.

**Address** Glasshouse, Alderley Park, Congleton Road Nether Alderley, Macclesfield, SK10 4ZE, Manchester, United Kingdom

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

10/09/2016 - 30/06/2019 Sheffield, United Kingdom

**BACHELOR'S OF ENGINEERING** Sheffield Hallam University

Address Howard St, Sheffield City Centre, Sheffield , S1 1WB, Sheffield, United Kingdom

Website https://www.shu.ac.uk/

12/09/2019 - 26/06/2022 Chester, United Kingdom

**MASTER OF SCIENCE** University of Chester

Website https://www.chester.ac.uk/

10/10/2023 - CURRENT York, United Kingdom

**DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY** University of York

Address Heslington, York, YO10 5DD, York, United Kingdom | Website https://www.york.ac.uk/

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ENGLISH** 

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
SPANISH	B1	B1	A2	A2	B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

## DIGITAL SKILLS

C++ | CUDA | Numpy | Matplotlib | PyTorch | Python | OpenCV | MATLAB | Algorithms & Data-structures | Micro-controllers | STM32 | sympy | Linux | AWS | GCP | Pandas | scipy | ROS | Isaac-gym | Git | Deep Learning | Machine Learning | Scikit-Learn | Artificial Intelligence | SQL | Data Science | Seaborn | Keras | Computer Vision | Data Analysis | Test-Driven-development | software metrics | UML-diagramming | ER-diagramming | Embedded C / Embedded Linux / RTOS / Testing Fundamentals / Confident using Raspberry pi | RTOS | Altium Designer, Xilinx, MS Office, AutoCAD, Micro-vision Keil, | AutoCAD and Inventor CAD program | CAD (FreeCAD)